# **MAHMOUD MAREY**

IT Infrastructure Manager

72 El-Naser St, El-Wailli , Abbasya 2 Abou El-Aswad st, El-Wailli , Abbasya +201011953864 Mmarey41189@gmail.com Mahmoudmarey41189@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahmoud-samirmaray-03266314

# **OBJECTIVE**

IT Infrastructure Manager with experience providing administrative support to over 10 staff members and have successfully led teams in designing and implementing network systems, managing and tunning server infrastructure, and optimizing IT operations to enhance efficiency and productivity. My technical expertise, along with my excellent communication and problem-solving skills, enable me to effectively collaborate with crossfunctional teams to achieve business goals.

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's Degree | Engineering

2007 - 2012

- Communication and Electronics Department with grade good (73.08%)
- Graduation Project: Home Security and Control Via SMS with grade Excellent

# **EXPERIENCE**

## IT INFRASTRUCTURE MANAGER | MISR LIFE INSURANCE

DEC. 2023 - PRESENT

- Infrastructure Management:
  - Design, implement, and maintain the IT infrastructure to support current operations and future growth.
  - Manage server infrastructure "PCA, SuperCluster, Exadata, HP, Lenovo", storage solutions "Oracle ZFS, IBM 7000, HP Alletra", Operating systems "Oracle Linux, Oracle Solaris, Microsoft OS suite for servers and client Administrations", End point protection "Kaspersky for client and Exchange servers" and network services.
  - Ensure high availability and reliability of IT systems and services.
  - Experience managing multiple locations.
- Cybersecurity:
  - Develop and implement comprehensive cybersecurity strategies and policies.
  - Monitor security threats and vulnerabilities and implement appropriate mitigation measures.
  - o Ensure compliance with industry regulations and standards (NIST, FRA).
  - o Conduct regular security assessments, audits, and penetration tests.
  - Manage incident response and disaster recovery plans.
- Network Administration:
  - Oversee the configuration, maintenance, and monitoring of network infrastructure, including routers, switches, firewalls, and VPNs.

- o Ensure network security and performance optimization.
- o Manage network-related projects, including upgrades and expansions.
- o Troubleshoot and resolve network issues promptly.

# System Administration:

- o Manage the installation, configuration, and maintenance of server hardware and software.
- Manage and administer Microsoft systems and services, including Windows Server, Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, and Group Policy and Exchange servers "2016-2019". Provide Tier 2/3 support for complex technical issues
- Microsoft 365 Administration: Design, implement, and manage Microsoft 365 solutions including Azure AD, Exchange Online, SharePoint Online, Teams, OneDrive for Business, and other Office 365 applications.
- o Ensure regular backups "Veritas" and disaster recovery solutions are in place and tested.
- Oversee user account management, including Active Directory and other authentication systems.
- o Implement and manage virtualization technologies.

#### • Team Leadership and Development:

- Lead and mentor a team of IT professionals, including network administrators, system administrators, and security analysts.
- Encourage continuous improvement and innovation within the IT infrastructure, including adopting new technologies and methodologies
- o Foster a culture of continuous improvement and professional development.
- o Conduct performance evaluations and provide feedback to team members.

#### Project Management:

- Plan and execute IT infrastructure projects, ensuring they are completed on time and within budget.
- Coordinate with other departments to understand their IT needs and provide appropriate solutions
- Maintain up-to-date documentation of IT systems and processes.
- Keep Server and Network diagram current

#### Vendor Management:

- Manage relationships with external vendors and service providers to ensure high-quality service delivery.
- o Budget Management
- Develop and manage the IT infrastructure budget, ensuring cost-effective use of resources

#### Senior System Administrator | Misr Life Insurance

JAN. 2020 - NOV. 2023

- SR. System Admin on Microsoft Environment (on-premises Microsoft Active Directory, Azure AD, DNS, DHCP, MS Exchange server 2013, 2016, 2019 and Online, WSUS, SCCM, SCOM) Microsoft windows (7,8,10,11) Microsoft Servers (2012 R2 2016 2019 2022) Microsoft Office (2013, 2016, 2019, O365)
- Microsoft Azure Security and Compliance administration
- Microsoft Azure Entra Administration and Protection
- Kaspersky Endpoint Protection Admin
- Project Manager for Designing Smart Branches
  - o Scope: Put the topology of the network
  - o Configure firewalls, switches, APs and join them with internal WAN.
  - Managing the passive works and the installation of (PCs, Laptops, IP telephony, MFP, APs, Cameras, ... etc.)

- Work on HP BladeSystem Administrator, VMWare, Hyper-V Manager, Failover Cluster Manager, Kaspersky Security Center Manager, Palo alto firewall, FortiGate (firewall, switches, APs)
- Monitor network performance (LAN, WAN) troubleshooting connection problems between sites and HQ.
- Technical support for (Laptops, PCs, Tablets, Printers, Scanners, ... etc.)

# System Administrator | Misr Life Insurance

APR. 2017 - DEC 2019

- System Admin on Microsoft Environment (on-premises Microsoft Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, MS
  Exchange server (2007,2013), WSUS, SCCM, SCOM) Microsoft windows (xp,7,10) Microsoft Servers
  (2008 2012 R2) Microsoft Office (2007,2013)
- Kaspersky Endpoint Protection Admin
- Work on HP BladeSystem Administrator, VMWare, Hyper-V Manager, Failover Cluster Manager, Kaspersky Security Center Manager, Palo alto firewall
- Monitor network performance (LAN, WAN) troubleshooting connection problems between sites and HO.
- Technical support for (Laptops, PCs, Tablets, Printers, Scanners, ... etc.)

### Technical Support Engineer | Vodafone Egypt

SEP. 2016 - MAR. 2017

Work as Technical Support Engineer

#### DSL:

- Work on Copper cabling cabinets and MSAN cabinets for improving the Vodafone DSL services form ISP to Customer
- Troubleshooting with the customer DSL inquiries and solving them.
- Configure ADSL modems remotely.
- Solving customer problems on the 1st level and 2nd level support
- Creating tickets for the premium or platinum cases

#### Mobile Data:

- Troubleshooting with customers 3G inquires on Smart Phones and USB stick modems.
- Monitoring the signaling performance for 3G, UMTS, HSPA, HSPA+ SIM cards
- Configuring SIM cards on the suitable modes for customer satisfaction
- Creating tickets to Wireless network team if the problem related to coverage signal area.

## Field Site Engineer | Alkan CIT (Vodafone Project)

JAN. 2015 - AUG. 2016

Work as field telecom engineer

- On Ericsson modules for 2G (2000 series and 6000 series) and on Ericsson module for 3G (2000 series, 3000 series and 6000 series)
- On Microwave links (SIAE)

- Scope:
  - Monitor the GSM site performance.
  - Maintaining down sites
  - o Configuring down sites with scripts or manual configuration
  - o Actions for replacement the faulty Microwave links
  - o Replacing the faulty module with a new one and configure it.
  - As a NFM engineer handles the shift (day night) with NFM's technicians for saving the GSM area clean from the environmental alarms.
  - Replacing the faulty rectifiers, making a battery test manually or scheduled battery test from rectifier
  - o Check site alarms and clear them.
  - Working on site logs and closing TT

## Field Site Engineer | Mobinil Egypt

MAY. 2012 - DEC. 2014

Work as Telecom Engineer

- On Motorola V1 & V2 for 2G
- Nokia Siemens Network (NSN) Modules 2G & 3G
- On Microwave links Alcatel Lucent & NEC (NEO) [V4, Compac, Standard] and NEC (IPaso 200, 400, 1000)
- Scope:
  - As a NFM engineer handles the shift (day night) with NFM's technicians for saving the GSM area clean from the environmental alarms.
  - o Maintaining down sites
  - o Actions for replacement the faulty Microwave links
  - Replacing the faulty module with a new one and configure it.
  - Replacing the faulty rectifiers, making a battery test manually or scheduled battery test from rectifier
  - o Check site alarms, clear them and close TT.

## **SKILLS**

- Microsoft 365
- Microsoft Azure
- Microsoft Entra ID
- Project Management
- Server Administration
- Group Policy
- Hyper-V
- Oracle VM
- SuperCluster VM
- FortiGate NGFW
- HP-Alletra Storage

- Windows Server 2012-2022
- Microsoft Exchange 2013-2019
- MS-SQL Administration
- MS-SQL implementation
- HP OneView Management
- Microsoft OS
- Oracle Linux OS
- Oracle Solaris OS
- IT Services
- Oracle ZFS Storage

- Infrastructure Management
- IT Leadership
- Vendor Relations
- Kaspersky Administration
- Failover Cluster Management
- OEM Monitor tool
- SCCM
- Arabic language (Mother tongue)
- English language (Very Good)